A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1934-1936
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1934-1936
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.491 II
This collection consists of 10,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred by the Office of the President, Pavilion VIII-East Lawn, University of Virginia on 1978 October 25.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Contents List
- General Files, 1934-1936
  - "A" Miscellaneous (anti-war material) 1934-1936 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Council (material re: Yellow Journal; anonymous, scurrilous, indecent, free speech) 1934-1936 (Box 1)
  - Aeronautics, National Advisory Committee on 1934-1936 (Box 1)
  - Alderman, Life of(correspondence of Dumas Malone) 1934-1936 (Box 1)
  - Alderman, Mrs. (correspondence to Newcomb re: Tuttle etchings) 1934-1936 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Foundation (Certificate of Incorporation) 1934-1936 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund--(organization plan of Alderman Alumni Fund) 1934-1936 (Box 2)
  - Alumni--General 1934-1936 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association--Board of Investments 1934-1936 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association--Board of Trustees (1of 2) 1934-1936 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association--Board of Trustees (2 of 2) 1934-1936 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Association--Contingent Fund 1934-1936 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Association--General Correspondence 1934-1936 (Box 3)
  - American Society of Civil Engineers 1934-1936 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports (faculty--regulations about forms) 1934-1936 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions 1934-1936 (Box 3)
  - Art and Architecture (Campbell correspondence and Edward Dean Richmond Gift; material re: houses, pictures, Virginia houses) 1934-1936 (Box 3)
  - Art and Architecture (1934) (Bayly Museum) 1934-1936 (Box 4)
  - Art and Architecture (1935-1936) (Bayly Museum) 1934-1936 (Box 4)
  - Articles on UVa. (A. Balz--statement re: quality of graduate dept.) 1934-1936 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities 1934-1936 (Box 4)
  - Astronomy (S. A. Mitchell correspondence) 1934-1936 (Box 4)
  - Athletics (1-2 of 3) (Southern Conference reports, plans of Presidents and Graham) 1934-1936 (Box 4)
  - Athletics (3 of 3) (1936) 1934-1936 (Box 5)
  - "B" Miscellaneous (1of 3) (needs of band; Baruch, Bernard--letters about son; Battle, George--general correspondence; Betts, Edwin M.--trees of the University) 1934-1936 (Box 5)
  - "B" Miscellaneous (2 of 3) 1934-1936 (Box 5)
  - "B" Miscellaneous (3 of 3) (Byrd, Harry F.--routine correspondence) 1934-1936 (Box 5)
  - Biology 1934-1936 (Box 6)
  - Biology--Mountain Lake (dedication exercises; historical sketch; annual reports; swimming curriculum) 1934-1936 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds (1934-1936)--forest correspondence with Hartman; repairs to building) 1934-1936 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Thornton Hall (Engineering Building) (money raised by P.W.A. bonds) 1934-1936 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds--he 1934-1936 (Box 7)
  - Bursar (1934-1936) (help for Mrs. page; Alderman Library; insurance policies; Rotunda repairs; private patient pavilion) 1934-1936 (Box 7)
  - Bursar--Burdick matter 1934-1936 (Box 7)
  - Bursar--Campbell note 1934-1936 (Box 7)
  - Bursar--Carruthers and President Newcomb (correspondence) 1934-1936 (Box 7)
  - Business Administration 1934-1936 (Box 8)
  - "C" Miscellaneous (2 folders) (Carroll Sparrow--article on heat; Case, O. V.--pecan trees [offspring of those planted by Jefferson]; cemetery accounts; College Topics; notice about peace Day-- Nov. 1, 1935; Commerce, State Chamber of; College of William and Mary--Alumni Association; Cincinnati Society medal and prize thesis; C.C.C.; Rivanna Clubs) 1934-1936 (Box 8)
  - Carnegie Foundation 1934-1936 (Box 8)
  - Carnegie Foundation and Carnegie Corporation (reports) 1934-1936 (Box 8)
  - Chemistry (weekly written quizzes; Dr. Richmond Bell's tenure) 1934-1936 (Box 8)
  - Choral Festival 1934-1936 (Box 8)
  - Church Society for College Work (minutes and correspondence) 1934-1936 (Box 8)
  - Commons (audit; need of boiler; sale of tickets) 1934-1936 (Box 9)
  - Convocations--(speakers: Bryan, John Stewart; Conant, James Bryant; Graham, Frank Porter) 1934-1936 (Box 9)
  - C.W.A. and W.P.A. (correspondence and papers re: administration of the program) 1934-1936 (Box 9)
  - "D" Miscellaneous ( Low Down, a scurrilous publication; suspension and expelling; peace strike--opposition; National Student League; stealing--vandalism; baseball injuries; A.A.U.W. gives financial aid to women students) 1934-1936 (Box 9)
  - Dean's Office (Ferguson and Lewis) 1934-1936 (Box 9)
  - Degree Requirements (notes re: revision) 1934-1936 (Box 9)
  - DuPont Trust 1934-1936 (Box 9)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (Echols, William H.--obituary; Eckenrode, H. J.--correspondence re: W.P.A. of Virginia writers project; Office of Education, Dept. of Interior) 1934-1936 (Box 9)
  - Education School (minutes of meetings; Va. Commission on Interracial Cooperation; tenure problems; rules for admission of women) 1934-1936 (Box 10)
  - Engineering School 1934-1936 (Box 10)
  - Engineering School (Pratt gift) 1934-1936 (Box 10)
  - English 1934-1936 (Box 10)
  - Extension School (1934) (Extension Committee Correspondence) 1934-1936 (Box 10)
  - Extension School (1935) 1934-1936 (Box 10)
  - Extension School (1936) 1934-1936 (Box 10)
  - "F" Miscellaneous (2 folders) (faculty meetings; General Faculty meetings; Intercollegiate Athletics Profiles; Flexner, Dr.--letter recommending Thomas P. Cook; Fine Arts--correspondence re: Cobb portrait; Frankfurter, Felix--TLS re: Roosevelt's speech at Monticello and AMS, thank-you note; Fraternity rushing, report of Bolling Powell [editor of Law Review]; Truman, Douglas S.--Campbell correspondence; Ambassade de la Republique Francaise re: medal struck for 100th Anniversary of Lafayette) 1934-1936 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1934-1936 (Box 10)
  - Finals 1934-1936 (Box 10)
  - Forestry (Ackerman correspondence) 1934-1936 (Box 11)
  - Forestry (Seward Forest) 1934-1936 (Box 11)
  - Forms 1934-1936 (Box 11)
  - Founder's Day (gifts; speakers: Hutchins, Robert; Colby, Bainbridge; Dodds, H. W.; Bowman, Isaiah) 1934-1936 (Box 11)
  - Fraternities (Beta Theta Pi--loan) 1934-1936 (Box 11)
  - "G" Miscellaneous (Gamble, Cary--to Newcomb re: Pearl S. Buck; Glass, Carter--to Newcomb [5 letters]; gift of squash courts--cost; Gooch, Robert K.--to Newcomb; Graham, Frank--to Newcomb: "Discussion of academic Freedom"; Gravatt--re: Ms. Janie Slaughter; Grenfell, Sir Wilfred--letter) 1934-1936 (Box 11)
  - General Education Board (requests for financial assistance) 1934-1936 (Box 12)
  - Geological Survey 1934-1936 (Box 12)
  - Geology (meeting of G.S.A.) 1934-1936 (Box 12)
  - Germanic Languages (general correspondence) 1934-1936 (Box 12)
  - German Scholars--Emergency Committee on Aid of 1934-1936 (Box 12)
  - Gifts (tables; portrait of Daniel Webster; Russian jewelry [McIntire]) 1934-1936 (Box 12)
  - Governor's Office (Newcomb to Gov. Perry, Negro applications for admission to U.Va.; Gov. Perry to Carruthers; general interchange) 1934-1936 (Box 12)
  - Graduate School Reorganization 1934-1936 (Box 12)
  - "H" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) (Hall, Sidney--correspondence to and from Newcomb; Hall of Fame--nomination of McCormick; Hampton Institute--invitation to visit; Healy--correspondence to and from Newcomb; Hall of Fame--nomination of McCormick; Hampton Institute--invitation to visit; Healy--correspondence with Newcomb re: McConnell portrait; Hennessey--scholarship) 1934-1936 (Box 12)
  - "H" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) (Hill, Julien--Newcomb, Metcalf re: graduate scholarship; Hopkins, Harry re: declined invitation to visit the University; Horsley to Byrd, R. E.--Peace Council; Horsley to Admiral Byrd--invitation to address peace rally in Richmond on 11 November 1936; Howard, D. H.--Estes Vaughan Scholarship; Howard University--rules about patents; Howard University Graduate School; Humanities Committee minutes; Hume, J. E. N.--correspondence re: General Electric donations to U.Va.; Hubert File--Forrest correspondence re: Hubert Grant) 1934-1936 (Box 13)
  - High School Visitations (lists of high schools and graduation requirements) 1934-1936 (Box 13)
  - History (Abernethy; Binkley and Barr--Shreve Fellowship; Wertenbaker; Wilson, Edith Bolling [2 letters]) 1934-1936 (Box 13)
  - Honor Courses (1of 2) (class attendance) 1934-1936 (Box 13)
  - Honor Courses (2 of 2) (Gooch on courses) 1934-1936 (Box 13)
  - Honor System (Thompson case--re: honor system at U.N.C.) 1934-1936 (Box 13)
  - Hospital--Addition (McIntire correspondence re: $7500 gift) 1934-1936 (Box 13)
  - "I" Miscellaneous (institutes; National Institute of Public Affairs, Institute of International Education, Institute of Higher learning; Insurance--T.I.S.A.; Prudential Insurance Company of America) 1934-1936 (Box 13)
  - Institute of Public Affairs (1of 3) (1935 Round Table topics; F.D. Roosevelt; signed letter of refusal; 1934 Round Table topics--correspondence re: J.B.N. Cardoza in reference to his book Constitution and the New Deal; history of institute; Maphis letters; Stettinius letter) 1934-1936 (Box 13)
  - Institute of Public Affairs (2of 3) (1936 Round Table--early letters re: Roosevelt 4th of July speech; Statistics 1933-1935; Barkley, Alben W.--partial acceptance; Peel affair) 1934-1936 (Box 14)
  - Institute of Public Affairs (3 of 3) (reports) 1934-1936 (Box 14)
  - Invitations (3 folders) 1934-1936 (Box 14)
  - "J" Miscellaneous ("Jabberwock"; Gones, R. Carter--re: unidentified English woman's description of UVa.; Jones, E.W.--Monroe Hill History) 1934-1936 (Box 14)
  - Jefferson bust by Houdon 1934-1936 (Box 15)
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation (Pres. Roosevelt to be at the grave) 1934-1936 (Box 15)
  - "K" Miscellaneous (Kappa Sigma Fraternity--liquor laws) 1934-1936 (Box 15)
  - "L" Miscellaneous (Lee, Lawrence--letter about J. S. Wilson; Le Jeune--correspondence w/ Newcomb; Athletics; Lewis, G.W.--Aviation Club organized; London, University of--Institution of History Research; Lyon, C.W. to Newcomb re: drawings) 1934-1936 (Box 15)
  - Labor Department (U.S.) 1934-1936 (Box 15)
  - Law School (2 folders) (bar exams; illness of Dean Dobie; Law Review; Allen Cox Murals; Dillard; Hardy; World peace Foundation) 1934-1936 (Box 15)
  - Lectures--Page-Barbour 1934-1936 (Box 15)
  - Lectures--(suggestions for lectures) 1934-1936 (Box 15)
  - Legal Papers (W.A. Perkins, attorney--Delta Chi Fraternity; Walter Randolph Estate; Page Manuscripts; Barnes Lumber Co. and Hollis Rinehart; Miller will) 1934-1936 (Box 15)
  - Legislative Program (budget, bills) 1934-1936 (Box 15)
  - Library (Anatomical Hall problem; McGregor Library [Clemmons letters]) 1934-1936 (Box 16)
  - "M" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) (movie shorts, out; MacDowell, M.--letter to Newcomb about invitation to colony; Madison Memorial Day--Clemmons' remarks on Madison, Monroe and Jefferson; Mason, Gabriel--committee on Academic Freedom, civil liberties, peace strike; McCarthy, Claire--training course in conducting community centers, College of William and Mary--McCormick portrait; McGuire, Murray--President of William and Mary, a position for Chapin Jones; McIntire, P.G.) 1934-1936 (Box 16)
  - "M" Miscellaneous (2of 2) (Miller, Francis--Wallace's speech, "T. Jefferson, Practical Idealist"; Minor, Venable--Beta Theta Pi [Va. Wooglin Co.]; Montgomery Advertiser--article on Tuskegee Institute; Moore, R. Walton--honor system, drinking at U.Va., prof. and students; Munn Paintings--letter of acceptance; Murfee, Hopson Owen--requests for information and copies of reports) 1934-1936 (Box 16)
  - Mathematics (Pineau letter; search for new member of department; copy of Veblen letter; need for topologist; outline of courses) 1934-1936 (Box 16)
  - McIntire Concerts (plans for National Symphony; the Old Harp Singers; Richmond Symphony) 1934-1936 (Box 16)
  - McIntire Fund (list of holdings; selling and buying) 1934-1936 (Box 16)
  - Medical Department (General) (invitation to Prof. Nystrom to visit U.Va. and acceptance; need of pharmacologist; Student health; Reply to editorial in College Topics; Lentz, Dr.--question Fr. Flypeus connection w/ drug companies; x-ray set-up; radiologist--position in Medical School; question and answers from other schools; Fauntleroy Scholarship; resignation of Dr. Goodwin; seal of the University; statement of needs in School of medicine; Smith, D.C--report of Department of Dermatology) 1934-1936 (Box 17)
  - Medical Department--Hospital--Nursing School (graduation exercises; Dietary dept.) 1934-1936 (Box 17)
  - Medical Department--Hospital Addition (2 folders) (bonds, maturities, interest; Campbell agreement for plans; P.W.A. project) 1934-1936 (Box 17)
  - Music (Carnegie gifts; record concerts) 1934-1936 (Box 17)
  - Music (Institute of Folklore and Music; Arthur Kyle Davis's work; John Powell letters [4]) 1934-1936 (Box 17)
  - "N" Miscellaneous (Nance, Mrs. W.V. re: University Tea Room; National Association of Deans and Advisors of members--resolution; Navy Bureau of Navigation--N.R.O.T.C. Naval league; Nelson, Robert F. to Newcomb re: mid-summer convention cruise; Faculty News Committee--lists, procedures, new members; News Leader--information about enrollment, new buildings faculty, where is Patrick Henry portrait?; New York College; statement of Newcomb re: American Student Union; Nobel Peace Prize--proposal of candidates; UNC--investigation into amateur standing of boxing squads of UVa. and UNC) 1934-1936 (Box 17)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Sigma Xi host at Va. program) 1934-1936 (Box 17)
  - National Association of State Universities (1-2 of 3) (correspondence re: arrangements for lobbying) 1934-1936 (Box 18)
  - National Youth Administration (3 of 3) (C.W.A. rules; part time employment; Southern Conference information) 1934-1936 (Box 18)
  - Negro Admissions and Scholarship Fund (rules of other Universities, notably Maryland; bill to provide equal education and facilities; Va. Commission of Interracial Cooperation [Dr. Tucker's committee]; Walter White to Dr. Dillard on Alice Jackson case; national Student League) 1934-1936 (Box 18)
  - "O" Miscellaneous (Oberlin College; Peace Institute meetings; posters; Oklahoma Agri.and Mech. College--faculty participation in administration; Owen, W.O.--relationship of Welsh and Indians) 1934-1936 (Box 18)
  - "P" Miscellaneous (2 folders) (Page collection--manuscripts; Page, Dean--statement of Newcomb; Pan Am. Union--Pan Am. Day; Parmelu, A.M.--papers and diary; Payne, Brude--discussion of Graduate Faculty; Phi Delta Kappa--history; Pickett, Deets--policy of U.Va. re: drinking; Pi Kappa Alpha--hung picture of Founder in Wilson room; Poe [Inv. Poe Soc.]--invitations to Festival for Peace; Pott, William S.--to Newcomb re: presidency of Elmira; Pratt, J.L.--Peralstine about Va., gold mine, correspondence with Newcomb; Price, Mrs. Walter--Col. Dames of America Scholarship) 1934-1936 (Box 18)
  - Patents Committee 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Personnel (survey) 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (list to be considered for membership; Constitution revised) 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Philosophy (suggestion to Dean of Graduate committee; resignation of Scott Buchanan) 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Physical Education (State Society of Phys. Ed. Convention; second annual Intramural Report; physical exams for Boxers) 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Physics (letters to S.A. Mitchell [copies--one from Einstein], program of work for Rockefeller grant; Bean's work) 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Political Science (conferences w/ J. Short; letters to and from Gooch; announcement of School of Poli. Sci.; National Science [Programme] conference invitation) 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Prospective Donors (named by friends and alumni; Maupin clock) 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Psychology 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Public Administration, Committee of 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Public Speaking (Committee to President Newcomb; candidates, recommendations) 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Questionnaires 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - "R" Miscellaneous (Real Estate--"Piedmont": is it for sale?; Rice Institute--question of faculty tenure; Rixey, Presley M.--gift of portrait of Admiral; Robertson, Stuart--Jefferson chair; Robinson, Morgan--Chapin Jones, degree for Newcomb from William and Mary; Rockfish Gap--market; Roosevelt, F.D.--to Pres. Newcomb re: social responsibilities of engineers; Roosevelt Theodore--memorial award, Rhodes Scholarship; Rosser, Thos. A.--report of Miller School; Rucker, Wm.--kindness of U.Va. students; Ruffty, Hilton--thanks for folk music lectures) 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Randolph, Bessie (to and from Newcomb) 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Raven Society--Awards Committee 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Recommendations (1 of 2) 1934-1936 (Box 19)
  - Recommendations (2 of 2) 1934-1936 (Box 20)
  - Research (Abernethy--statement about research at U.Va.; Balz--report of Research Committee) 1934-1936 (Box 20)
  - Romance Languages (Italian student exchange; Faculty news Committee; Italian government gives books) 1934-1936 (Box 20)
  - ROTC (protest against it by College Topics, Jefferson Society, National Students League, Senior Cabinet of Madison Hall) 1934-1936 (Box 20)
  - Ryan Estate (portraits bequeathed to --permission to leave during Mrs. Ryan's life) 1934-1936 (Box 20)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (3 folders) (Saville, Allen J.--plan for Engineering Building; need of e. of people about public administration; Schepers, Hon--questions about Serpentine Wall; Scott, Frederick W.--to and from Newcomb; Dulaney's book review; Scott, James H.--to and from Newcomb; Seismological Society of America--resolution; Student Senate and Assembly--new Constitution; Shepperson, Phillippa B.--Bruce portrait to be copied; Sigma Nu--loan; Sigma Xi--President and Visitors Research prize (Speidel), new members, list of resident members, invitation to National Academy of Science by Sigma Xi, new members; Smith, Howard--letters to and from Newcomb; Smith, L.O.--anti-hazing Law; Smith, W. Kyle--"Parsonage"; Speicher, Eugene--hand-written letter about portrait of Alderman; Stauffer, Wm. H.--analysis of educational costs; Stettinius, Edward to Pres. Newcomb--re: Dean Page, W.S. Pott [letter and telegram], Babson's report re: Board of Visitors membership; Stone, Charles A.--introduction to Count Camerana; Storey, Thomas--notes on service for the prevention and care of athletic injuries; Stratford hall--dedication; Student Union--constitution; Swan, Alfred--Countess Tolstoy to lecture under auspices of A.A.U.W.) 1934-1936 (Box 20)
  - Scholarships (Rhodes--applicants) 1934-1936 (Box 20)
  - Scholarships (Ryan--list of applicants) 1934-1936 (Box 20)
  - Scholarships (Tiffany--interpretation of will) 1934-1936 (Box 20)
  - Sociology (Phelps-Stokes Fellowship; Social Science Group meeting) 1934-1936 (Box 20)
  - Social Sciences (4 folders) (Institute for Research, report of 1st 10 years; Agenda of meetings of Council of the Institute and for research in the social sciences; UVa.--a decade of organized social science research by Wilson Gee; annual report; Bureau of Public Administration; Institute for public research applications and recommendations; statement of Egger, Reed, Altman, and Bromage--outline of position; resolution commending UVa. for the accomplishments of its Bureau of Public Administration and urging its continuance; Institute for Public Research--addenda; meeting of executive committee; annual report--Gee; "A State Library Plan"; temporary budget; Stacy May Letters) 1934-1936 (Box 21)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools (plans for meeting; need for Southern Conference meeting; study of Catawba College) 1934-1936 (Box 21)
  - Speeches (Miscellaneous) 1934-1936 (Box 21)
  - Statistics (general about UVa.) 1934-1936 (Box 21)
  - Stauffer, William H. (2 folders)--"Report", correspondence, material collected by Wilson Gee) 1934-1936 (Box 21)
  - Sullivan Foundation Award (Reither, Roy Mason; list o awards 1928-1934) 1934-1936 (Box 22)
  - Summer Session (conference on education; institutes; expenses; teacher retirement law revision) 1934-1936 (Box 22)
  - "T" Miscellaneous (2 folders) (Taylor, Charles F.--football cleaning up; Taylor, Robert C.--to and from Newcomb; Taylor, Robert S.--football w/ Georgetown; T.I.A.A. (Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association)--information to go to BOV; Thomas, Henry--approval of new athletic plan; Thornton, William Minor--correspondence: resolution on death, plan for funeral, letters to Newcomb including offer of J. S. Wilson to borrow Jefferson portrait from Bowdoin; history of University School of Engineering [unbound in English dept. file]; Holsinger--trustee of Isobel Merrick Scholarship; Thurman, Francis Lee--to Newcomb re: new buildings; Trinkle, E. Lee--Is Government placing men and women in UVa.; Troubetskoy, Pierre--sale of Castle Hill; Trout, Hugh--Rotunda for Jefferson papers; Tucker, Beverly R.--correspondence; Tunstall, Robert B.--all subjects, newsletter--"Virginia's Revised School Curriculum", alumni, Stone Library; P.W.A. loan; Tuskegee--questionnaire and request for Catalogue) 1934-1936 (Box 22)
  - Taliafero Estate 1934-1936 (Box 22)
  - "U" Miscellaneous (United Daughters of the Confederacy--University Prize; University Christian Association--speaker, Dr. Francis P. Miller--University Houses) 1934-1936 (Box 22)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (Van Landingham, John--note re: Seward chairs; Van Valkenberg, W.D.; Va. Academy of Sciences--invitation to meet at; Va. Association of preparatory Schools--meeting at Madison Hall; Va. Education Society--Public Relations Committee, article on Dean Page; Va. law Review--included in tuition; V.M.I.--Hunter Pendleton retirement; V.P.I.--graduation requirements) 1934-1936 (Box 22)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review(donors, underwriters, report of Lambert Davis) 1934-1936 (Box 22)
  - Visitors (4 folders) (meeting announcements; faculty minutes; admission of blacks; "Morea"; library plans; Stauffer report; Mountain Lake Biology Station; McIntire resignation; Houdon statue; Dean Richmond bequest; ROTC) 1934-1936 (Box 23)
  - "W" Miscellaneous (2 folders) (Walter, G. Carter--Headmaster's Association; Wall, Mrs. Louise--Arnold, Forster to visit [Peace Movement]; Wallace, H.A.--[dept. of Agriculture] invited to speak; Walp, Paul K.--League of Nations Association, Peace Day meeting; War Department--withhold enactment because of discriminatory character; Warner, G.C.--Dyer paintings; Wertenbaker, T.J.; Wheeler--Bennett, John; White William H.--labor foundation, athletics--Graham's plan; White Top--folk festival; Whiting, Gertrude--Leutze paintings; Wickham, Littleton--wording of Tablet; Wilkins, Ernest H.--resolution of Pres. of Colleges; of folk music research; William, Eustace--background for movie; Williams, Charles--Hampton Institute, letters from Dr. Frissell to Alderman; Williams, R. Gray; Williamson, Lee H.--Holmes papers; Wilson, James Southall--life and work of Dean Page; Wilson, P. St. Julien--to Newcomb re: Cocke photograph; Wisconsin, Univ. of--President Glenn Frank statements; Wood, Florence--correspondence re: Jefferson's dressing gown) 1934-1936 (Box 23)
  - White, William H.--Foundation (speakers and publishing books) 1934-1936 (Box 23)